Guide to the American Business Consultants, Inc. Counterattack: Research Files TAM 148
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series 14.1: Individuals Named.
  - Strauss, Leon, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 14-120)
  - *Baldwin, Roger N., 1948-1949 (Box 27, Folder 14-121)
  - Stowe, Leland, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 14-122)
  - Sentner, William, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 14-123)
  - Spofford, Rev.William B., 1948 (Box 27, Folder 14-124)
  - *Foner- Philip S., Henry J., Jack, Morris (Moe), 1948-1949 (Box 27, Folder 14-125)
  - Ross, Paul, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 14-126)
  - *Hiss, Alger, 1948-1952 (Box 27, Folder 14-127)
  - *Schrank, Robert, 1948-1949 (Box 27, Folder 14-128)
  - Shapley, Harlow, 1949-1952 (Box 27, Folder 14-129)
  - *Nixon, Russell A., 1949-1953 (Box 27, Folder 14-130)
  - Emerson, Thomas I., 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-131)
  - Smith, Edwin Seymour, 1949-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-132)
  - Urey, Dr. Harold C., 1949-1953 (Box 28, Folder 14-133)
  - Gauss, Dean Christian, 1948? (Box 28, Folder 14-134)
  - Mann, Thomas, 1947-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-135)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, undated (Box 28, Folder 14-136)
  - Rubinstein, Dr. Annette, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-137)
  - Boas, Dr. Ernst P., 1947 (Box 28, Folder 14-138)
  - Davis, Michael M., undated (Box 28, Folder 14-139)
  - Webster, Margaret, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-140)
  - Parker, Dorothy, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-141)
  - Snow, Edgar, 1947-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-142)
  - *Gayn, Mark (Ginsburgh), 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-143)
  - Lustig, James, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-144)
  - *Scherer, Marcel, 1947-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-145)
  - Berenholz, Anne, 1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-146)
  - Yanoff, Morris, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-147)
  - Hirschmann, Ira Archer, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-148)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B., 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-149)
  - Loeb, Philip, 1949-1952 (Box 28, Folder 14-150)
  - Linfield, Seymour, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-151)
  - Fast, Howard, 1947-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-152)
  - DuBois, W.E.B., 1948-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-153)
  - Bass, Mrs. Charlotta A., 1948 (Box 28, Folder 14-154)
  - Lauterbach, Richard E., 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-155)
  - Downes, Olin, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-156)
  - Stewart, Donald Ogden, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-157)
  - *Adler, Larry, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-158)
  - Sweets, William M., 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-159)
  - Lathrop, Rev. John Howland, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-160)
  - Roe, Wellingon, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-161)
  - Steel, Johannes (Herbert Stahl), 1946-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-162)
  - Johnson, Rev. Hewlett, 1948-1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-163)
  - Field, Marshall, 1947-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-164)
  - Bridges, Harry, 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-165)
  - Benson, Elmer A., 1948 (Box 28, Folder 14-166)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-167)
  - *Wise, Rabbi Stephen S., 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-168)
  - Christoffel, Harold R., 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-169)
  - Strong, Anna Louise, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-170)
  - Melish, Rev. William Howard, 1947-1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-171)
  - Crouch, Paul, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-172)
  - Connally, Eugene P., 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-173)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-174)
  - *Clark, Tom C., 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-175)
  - *Crosbie, Paul, 1945-1948 (Box 28, Folder 14-176)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-177)
  - Brand, Millen, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-178)
  - DaSilva, Howard, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-179)
  - Remington, William W., 1948-1953 (Box 28, Folder 14-180)
  - Commager, Henry Steele, 1948-1953 (Box 28, Folder 14-181)
  - Jandreau, Leo, 1947-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-182)
  - *Jaffe, Henry & Jean Muir, 1936-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-183)
  - Van Doren, Mark, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-184)
  - *Pomerantz, Abraham L., 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-185)
  - *Bridges, Harry, 1949-1953 (Box 28, Folder 14-186)
  - *Brand, Oscar, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-187)
  - *Brown, Cecil, 1942-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-188)
  - Davidson, Jo, 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-189)
  - Davis, Dr. Herbert John, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-190)
  - *Drake, Alfred, 1948-1953 (Box 28, Folder 14-191)
  - *Dean, Verea Micheles, 1947-1960 (Box 28, Folder 14-192)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1948-1953 (Box 28, Folder 14-193)
  - Graham, Dr. Frank P., 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-194)
  - Grauer, Ben, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-195)
  - Ferrer, Jose, 1948-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-196)
  - Field, Frederick Vanderbilt, 1949-1953 (Box 28, Folder 14-197)
  - Foye, Hope, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-198)
  - Freistadt, Hans, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-199)
  - Gannett, Betty, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-200)
  - Guinier, Ewart, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-201)
  - *Holliday, Judy, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-202)
  - Hagen, Uta, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-203)
  - Hammett, Dashiell, 1951-1953 (Box 28, Folder 14-204)
  - Houseman, John, 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-205)
  - Hovda, Bryn J., 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-206)
  - *Hunt, Marsha, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-207)
  - *Isaacs, Stanley M., 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-208)
  - Ives, Burl, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-209)
  - *Jessup, Philip C., 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 14-210)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-211)
  - Johnson, Mrs. Beatrice Siskind, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-212)
  - Jones, Rev. John Paul, 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-213)
  - Kasenkina, Mrs. Oksana, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 14-214)
  - Kahn, Albert E., 1946-1948 (Box 28, Folder 14-215)
  - *+Kamp, Koseph P., 1945-1954 (Box 28, Folder 14-216)
  - *Kraber, Tony Gerrit and Wilhelmina Kraber, 1948-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-217)
  - Kravchenko, Victor, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-218)
  - Kent, Rockewell, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 14-219)
  - *Reuter, Madalynne, 1949-1951 (Box 28, Folder 14-220)
  - *Michelson, Clarina, 1949-1951 (Box 29, Folder 14-221)
  - *Lamont, Corliss, 1941-1954 (Box 29, Folder 14-222)
  - Lancaster, Burt, 1948-1950 (Box 29, Folder 14-223)
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1943-1953 (Box 29, Folder 14-224)
  - Lavery, Emmett, 1947-1951 (Box 29, Folder 14-225)
  - Lee, Gypsy Rose, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 14-226)
  - Leslie, Kenneth, 1944-1946 (Box 29, Folder 14-228)
  - Lev, Ray, 1949-1951 (Box 29, Folder 14-229)
  - Lewis, Fulton Jr., 1949-1951 (Box 29, Folder 14-230)
  - Santo, John, 1947-1949 (Box 29, Folder 14-231)
  - Sacher, Harry, 1949-1953 (Box 29, Folder 14-231A)
  - *Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel, 1952-1953 (Box 29, Folder 14-232)
  - *Stone, I. F., 1946-1955 (Box 29, Folder 14-233)
  - +Thomas, J. Parnell, 1947-1949 (Box 29, Folder 14-234)
  - *Warne, Colston E., 1950 (Box 29, Folder 14-235)
  - Weinberg, Joseph W., 1949 (Box 29, Folder 14-236)
  - *Weltfish, Dr. Gene, 1948-1951 (Box 29, Folder 14-237)
  - missing folder, undated (Box 29, Folder 14-238)
  - *Hubley, John, 1948-1956 (Box 29, Folder 14-239)
- Series 15: Organizations Miscellaneous (arranged by file#); See also, Series 50, Organizations, Misc - alphabetical arrangement.
  - (pg# 1-134 ) Mimi, where are the sheets for these? I may have mislaid my copy (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - (pg# 135 ) National Arts Foundation, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - (pg# 136 ) United World Federalists, undated (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - (pg# 137 ) Foundation for Economic Education, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - (pg# 138 ) American Relief for Korea, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - (pg# 139 ) Thomas Paine Foundation, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - (pg# 140 ) National Meeting of the Engineer and Scientists of American Union, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - (pg# 141-149 ) Threefold - A Movement Opposing Social Centralization, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - (pg# 150 ) American Institute for Economic Research, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - +Non-Communist Essentials for Trade Unionism, 1949? (Box 29, Folder 15-0)
  - +American Legion, 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-1)
  - Catholic Chruch (Vatican), 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-2)
  - Plain Talk, 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-3)
  - Government Officials, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 15-4)
  - +National Majority (United White Collar Majority), 1945-1946 (Box 29, Folder 15-5)
  - +Speech Material (J.Q.A., i.e. John Quincy Adams Associates), 1946 (Box 29, Folder 15-6)
  - National Institute of Social Relations, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 15-7)
  - *+John Quincy Adams Associates, 1946-1949 (Box 29, Folder 15-8)
  - Committee for Democratic Trade Unionism, CIO, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-9)
  - *American Veterans Committee, 1946-1953 (Box 29, Folder 15-10)
  - Atomic Energy Control Commission, 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-11)
  - +Rev. John F. Cronin, 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-12)
  - *Rev. Andrew P. Maloney, 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-13)
  - Regelson, Joseph, 1943-1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-14)
  - Missing folders, undated (Box 29, Folder 15-15, 16)
  - *Hawkins, Gardiner, 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-17)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-18)
  - Horn, Sampson, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 15-19)
  - Coplon-Gubitchev Case (1st trial, 4/25/1949) (Box 29, Folder 15-20)
  - Alger Hiss trial (1st, 5/3/1949) (Box 29, Folder 15-21)
  - *+Reference material on compulsory sickness insurance (issued by the National Physician's Committee for the Extension of Medical Service), 1942-1945 (Box 29, Folder 15-22)
  - *+Medical Services Foundation; National Physicians Committee, 1947-1949 (Box 30, Folder 15-22A)
  - +"Newsletter", 1947 (Box 30, Folder 15-23)
  - +Counterattack - Publicity, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 15-23A)
  - Free enterprise - planned economy, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 15-24)
  - Missing folder, undated (Box 30, Folder 15-25)
  - PM, 1940-1946 (Box 30, Folder 15-26)
  - Youthbuilders, 1945-1946 (Box 30, Folder 15-27)
  - *Americans for Democratic Action, 1946-1959 (Box 30, Folder 15-28)
  - Council Against Intolerance in America, 1946-1948 (Box 30, Folder 15-29)
  - Missing folder, undated (Box 30, Folder 15-30)
  - Universities, colleges, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 15-31)
  - *City College of New York, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 15-31A)
  - Friends of Democracy, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 15-32)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1947-1954 (Box 30, Folder 15-33)
  - *American Civil Liberties Union, 1955-1956 (Box 30, Folder 15-33/Supp.A)
  - *American Civil Liberties Union, 1947-1949 (Box 30, Folder 15-33/Supp.B)
  - *American China Policy Association, 1946-1949 (Box 30, Folder 15-34)
  - *+American Jewish League Against Communism, 1948-1949 (Box 30, Folder 15-35)
  - American Rally, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 15-36)
- Series 50: Organizations, Miscellaneous (arranged alphabetically); see also, series 15: Organizations, Miscellaneous - arranged by file#.
  - No (or missing?) folders for these #s, undated (Box 30, Folder 50-0 thru 15-159)
  - + Tablet editorials, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 50-160)
  - Taiwan - Red China, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 50-161)
  - Union Racketeering, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 50-162)
  - The United Nations and the United Automibile Workers, 1958-1965 (Box 30, Folder 50-163)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), 1955-1961 (Box 30, Folder 50-164)
  - Unitarians, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 50-165)
  - *Upholsterers International Union of America, 1957-1959 (Box 30, Folder 50-166)
  - Van Horne, Harriet, 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 50-167)
  - *Wanamakers' Department Sotre Employees Union, 1949-1953 (Box 30, Folder 50-168)
  - *+Wingenback, Charles E., 1957-1958 (Box 30, Folder 50-169)
  - World Court, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 50-170)
  - World Peace Through Law Center, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 50-171)
  - World Youth Festival. 6th, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 50-172)
  - *Crockett, William J., 1950-1965 (Box 30, Folder 50-173)
  - Yale University, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 50-174)
  - *+Council Against Communist Agression; Alexis de Tocqueville Society, 1958-1964 (Box 30, Folder 50-175)
- Series 16: Espionage, Russian.
  - Espionage, Russian, 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 16-1)
- Series 17: U.S. Government Agencies
  - Government Agencies, Misc (empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 17-0)
  - State Dept. (Empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 17-1)
  - Treasury Dept. (Empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 17-2)
  - Defense Dept. (Empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 17-3)
  - Justice Dept., 1949 (Box 31, Folder 17-4)
  - Post Office (Empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 17-5)
  - Interior Dept. (Empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 17-6)
  - Agriculture Dept. (Empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 17-7)
  - Commerce Dept. (Empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 17-8)
  - Labor, Dept. Of, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 17-9)
- Series 18: Trotskyism.
  - Trotskyism, 1937-1947 (Box 31, Folder 18-0)
  - Socialist Workers Party, 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 18-1)
- Series 19: Facism.
  - Fascism, undated (Box 31, Folder 19-1)
- Series 20: Public Opinion
  - Public Opinion, 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 20-0)
- Series 21: Foundations
  - List of Foundations, undated (Box 31, Folder 21-)
  - Joint and general references, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 21-0-A)
  - Joint and general references, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 21-0-B)
  - Joint and general references, 1950-1952 (Box 31, Folder 21-0-C)
  - American Fund for Public Service, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 21-1)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 21-2)
  - Carnegie Endowment of International Peace, undated (Box 31, Folder 21-3)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching (empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 21-4)
  - Field Foundation, undated (Box 31, Folder 21-5)
  - Edward A. Filene Good Will Fund, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 21-6)
  - Daniel and Florence Guggenheim Foundation (empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 21-7)
  - Simon John Guggenheim Foundation, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 21-8)
  - Solomon R. Guggenheim Foundation (empty folder), undated (Box 31, Folder 21-9)
  - Robert Marshall Civil Liberties Trust, undated (Box 31, Folder 21-10)
  - Robert Marshall Civil Liberties Foundaton, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 21-11)
  - Robert Marshall Wilderness Fund, undated (Box 31, Folder 21-12)
  - *Rockefeller Foundation, 1947-1949 (Box 31, Folder 21-13)
  - *Rockefeller University, 1943-1944 (Box 31, Folder 21-13-A)
  - Julius Rosenwald Fund, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 21-14)
  - *Russell Sage Foundation, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 21-15)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 21-16-v.1)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 21-16-v.2)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1940-1946 (Box 32, Folder 21-16-v.3)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Publiciations, 1943-1947 (Box 32, Folder 21-16-1A)
  - Soundview Foundation (empty folder), undated (Box 32, Folder 21-17)
  - *Twentieth Century Fund, 1947-1966 (Box 32, Folder 21-18)
  - William C. Whitney Foundation, 1942-1947 (Box 32, Folder 21-19)
  - Ford Foundation, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 21-20)
  - California Intelligence Bureau, 1953-1953 (Box 32, Folder 21-20?)
- Series 22: Miscellaneous - includes: doctors, interns, others.
  - *Communist Party of New York, 1949-1954 (Box 32, Folder 22-1)
  - Unions - Retail Drug Employees Union, etc., undated (Box 32, Folder 22-2)
  - League of Women Voters, 1952-1954 (Box 32, Folder 22-3)
  - *+Medicine - Opposition to Health Insurance - Physicians Forum, undated (Box 32, Folder 22-4)
  - Association of Internes and Medical Students, 1947-1952 (Box 32)
  - World Documentary Films, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 22-5)
  - *+Circuit Riders, Inc., 1954-1955 (Box 32, Folder 22-6)
  - New York Civil Liberties Union, 1954 (Box 32, Folder 22-7)
  - +Hate Groups, 1950-1955 (Box 32, Folder 22-8)
- Series 23: Ralph Bunche
  - Ddr. Ralph Bunche, 1954 (Box 32, Folder 23-1)
- Series 24: Unknown
  - Subversive Groups, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 24-)
- Series 50: Organizations, Miscellaneous (arranged alphabetically); see also, series 15: Organizations, Miscellaneous - arranged by file#.
  - "Old man atom" (song) /Tenants & consumers organizations, undated (Box 33, Folder 50-1)
  - *Screen Cartoonists (Guild), 1946-1950 (Box 33, Folder 50-2)
  - *Farmers Union, 1947-1955 (Box 33, Folder 50-3)
  - *American Communications Association, 1946-1954 (Box 33, Folder 50-4)
  - Challenge /New Challenge (Labor Youth League), undated (Box 33, Folder 50-5)
  - *Consumers Union, 1941-1951 (Box 33, Folder 50-6)
  - *United Financial Employees, U.O.P.W.A., 1946-1950 (Box 33, Folder 50-7)
  - U.O.P.W.A. & Bankers Trust Strike, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 50-8)
  - People's Artists /Art Editions /, 1951-1955 (Box 33, Folder 50-9)
  - Dave Beck, investigation of (Teamsters), 1957 (Box 33, Folder 50-10)
  - National Student Association, 1947-1955 (Box 33, Folder 50-11)
  - CP leaders, group 3, California, 1951-1952 (Box 33, Folder 50-12)
  - CP leaders, group 4, Baltimore, 1951-1953 (Box 33, Folder 50-13)
  - CP leaders, group 5, Pittsburgh, 1950-1953 (Box 33, Folder 50-14)
  - CP leaders, group 6, Honolulu, 1952-1953 (Box 33, Folder 50-15)
  - CP leaders, group 8, Detroit, 1952-1954 (Box 33, Folder 50-16)
  - CP leaders, group 9, Seattle, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 50-17)
  - CP leaders, group 10, St. Louis, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 50-18)
  - CP leaders, group 11, Philadelphia, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 50-19)
  - CP leaders, group 12, Cleveland, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 50-20)
  - CP leaders, group 13, Cleveland (empty folder), undated (Box 33, Folder 50-21)
  - YNCA - YWCA, 1948-1949 (Box 33, Folder 50-22)
  - Youth Problems, Inc.; Youthbuilders, Inc., 1946-1950 (Box 33, Folder 50-23)
  - *Young Progressives of America, 1948-1950 (Box 33, Folder 50-24)
  - American Association of Scientific Workers, 1950-1954 (Box 33, Folder 50-25)
  - Missing folder, undated (Box 33, Folder 50-26)
  - *Artists' Equity Association, 1948-1955 (Box 33, Folder 50-27)
  - *Letters of denial via McNamara, 1948-1956 (Box 33, Folder 50-28)
  - *Young People's Records, Inc., 1948-1950 (Box 33, Folder 50-29)
  - *Young People's Record Club, 1948-1950 (Box 33, Folder 50-30)
  - *Names - Miscellaneous Reports, A-Z, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 50-31)
  - Organizatioans - Miscellaneous Reports, A-Z, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 50-32)
  - *Illinois, Feb. 4, 1946 - Feb. 13, 1948, 1946-1948 (Box 33, Folder 50-33.v1)
  - *Illinois, Feb. 17, 1948 - Sept. 9, 1948, 1946-1948 (Box 33, Folder 50-33.v2)
  - *Illinois, Sept. 2, 1948 - June 29, 1949, 1948-1949 (Box 34, Folder 50-33.v3)
  - *Illinois, July 1, 1949 - Oct. 20, 1950, 1949-1950 (Box 34, Folder 50-33.v4)
  - Americna Civil Liberties Union, 1949-1967 (Box 34, Folder 50-34)
  - American Bar Association, 1959-1965 (Box 34, Folder 50-35)
  - *American Communication Association, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 50-36)
  - American Forum for Socialist Education, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 50-37)
  - +All-American Conference to Combat Communism, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 50-38)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, 1956-1965 (Box 34, Folder 50-39)
  - +American Friends of Captive Nations, 1956-1958 (Box 34, Folder 50-40)
  - *American Newspaper Guild, 1947-1957 (Box 34, Folder 50-41)
  - The American Socialist, 1955-1958 (Box 34, Folder 50-42)
  - American Foundation for Political Education, 1957-1958 (Box 34, Folder 50-43)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1954-1958 (Box 34, Folder 50-44)
  - American mothers visit sons in China prisons, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 50-45)
  - *+Anti-Communist Legislation, 1950-1954 (Box 34, Folder 50-46)
  - Atomic Bombs and Missiles, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 50-47)
  - Re Attorney General's List, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 50-48)
  - Max Ascoli and The Reporter, 1950-1954 (Box 34, Folder 50-49)
  - Canadian Communism, 1949-1954 (Box 34, Folder 50-50)
  - Alinsky, Saul, 1965-1967 (Box 34, Folder 50-51)
  - Art Students' League, 1964-1965 (Box 34, Folder 50-52)
  - *Bettis, Valerie, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 50-53)
  - Bakers' Union, 1946-1954 (Box 34, Folder 50-54)
  - Barenblatt, Lloyd, 1958-1959 (Box 34, Folder 50-55)
  - Bildenberg Group, conferences, 1957-1965 (Box 34, Folder 50-56)
  - +John Birch Society, 1964-1965 (Box 34, Folder 50-57)
  - Books, undated (Box 34, Folder 50-58)
  - Heywood Broun Memorial Award, 1948-1958 (Box 34, Folder 50-59)
  - Brussels International Trade Fair, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 50-60)
  - *+Louis Budenz' column ("The Reds - What Now?" in The Tablet), 1958-1959 (Box 34, Folder 50-61)
  - California Institute of Technology, 1950 (Box 34, Folder 50-62)
  - Canadian Intelligence Service, 1965-1967 (Box 34, Folder 50-63)
  - *Catherwood Foundation, 1955-1956 (Box 34, Folder 50-64)
  - +Christian Anti-Communism Crusade, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 50-65)
  - Chicagao,, University of, 1950-1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-66)
  - +Circuit Riders, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-67)
  - +"The Communist Party, USA" (manuscript), 1965 (Box 35, Folder 50-68)
  - Communist Party, USA. 16th National Convention, 1955-1957 (Box 35, Folder 50-69)
  - +Congress of Freedom, Inc., 1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-70)
  - +Council Against Communist Agression, 1957-1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-71)
  - Council for a Livable World, 1964-1965 (Box 35, Folder 50-72)
  - Cultural Exchange with Russia, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-73)
  - Elmer Davis Memorial Committee, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-74)
  - +Let Freedom Ring, 1965-1966 (Box 35, Folder 50-75)
  - Dewey, Thomas E. Jr., 1964 (Box 35, Folder 50-76)
  - du Berrier, Hilaire, 1955-1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-77)
  - *Downtown Community School, 1953-1955 (Box 35, Folder 50-78)
  - *Eaton, Cyrus, 1951-1960 (Box 35, Folder 50-79)
  - Eichelberger, Ted, 1953-1954 (Box 35, Folder 50-80)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1955-1965 (Box 35, Folder 50-81)
  - FBI, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 50-82)
  - Flouridation, 1954-1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-83)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1961-1966 (Box 35, Folder 50-84)
  - Fund for the Republic, 1952-1965 (Box 35, Folder 50-85)
  - *Gordon Hall, 1947-1964 (Box 35, Folder 50-86)
  - Harvard law School, 1957-1959 (Box 35, Folder 50-87)
  - Harvard University, 1950-1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-88)
  - *Hawaii Residents Association (aka "Imua," i.e. "Go forward" in Hawaiian), 1949-1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-89)
  - * IMUA Spotlight(Hawaiian Residents Association), 1950-1953 (Box 35, Folder 50-90)
  - Health Research - California, undated (Box 35, Folder 50-91)
  - Heikkila, William, 1957-1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-92)
  - HUAC, 1952-1955 (Box 35, Folder 50-92)
  - General Hugh B. Hester, 1957-1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-94)
  - *Highlander Folk School, 1953-1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-95)
  - Hillman, Sideny, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 50-96)
  - *Hiss, Alger, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 50-97)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar & FBI, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 50-98)
  - Hydrogen Bomb, Nuclear Fallout, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-99)
  - *+Immigration, 1950-1967 (Box 35, Folder 50-100)
  - Jews - Birobidzhan, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-101)
  - *Johnson - Syracuse, 1954-1955 (Box 35, Folder 50-102)
  - *Kerbs, Mrs. Jeanne E., 1959-1967 (Box 35, Folder 50-103)
  - Kirstein, George G., 1959 (Box 35, Folder 50-104)
  - Knowland, Sen. William F., 1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-105)
  - *Lamont, Corliss, 1952-1955 (Box 35, Folder 50-106)
  - Emma Lazarus Federation of Jewish Women's Clubs, 1957=1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-107)
  - League of Women Voters, 1955-1965 (Box 35, Folder 50-108)
  - Liberty Book Club, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 50-109)
  - McCarran Act, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 50-110)
  - *McCormack, Rev. Peter, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 50-111)
  - *McCullough, Hester R., 1949-1950 (Box 35, Folder 50-112)
  - Meagher, Robert, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 50-113)
  - Mental Health, 1950-1960 (Box 36, Folder 50-114)
  - *Methodist Federation for Social Action, 1947-1960 (Box 36, Folder 50-115)
  - Methodist Ministes, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 50-116)
  - Mexico, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 50-117)
  - Militant Labor Forum, undated (Box 36, Folder 50-118)
  - Milwaukee Journal, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 50-119)
  - *Musician's Local 802; President Al Manuti, 1937-1958 (Box 36, Folder 50-120)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 50-121)
  - *National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, 1958-1960 (Box 36, Folder 50-122)
  - National Committee to Win Amnesty for the Smith Act Victims, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 50-123)